<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Intro to Social Data Science</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/isds2024/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Intro to Social Data Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/isds2024/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Assignments</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/isds2024/post/assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/isds2024/post/assignment/</guid>
      <description>This post contain practical information related to each of the three assignments. Check back later for news about deadlines and other assignment related information. All assignments must be handed via Absalon here.&#xA;Assignment 0: Available June 28. Deadline July 27 @ 12.00&#xA;Assignment 1: Available August 2. Deadline August 4 @ 23.59&#xA;Assignment 2: Available August 8. Deadline August 11 @ 23.59</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/isds2024/post/install/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/isds2024/post/install/</guid>
      <description>This class will involve a lot of coding, for which you will need some basic tools.&#xA;Python, Jupyter Notebook and JupyterLab A git client A github account We will discuss these tools in much more detail in class, so don&amp;rsquo;t worry if this is all new and perhaps a bit frightening right now.&#xA;Python, Jupyter Notebook and JupyterLab Python is a free programming language. We will use the distribution called Anaconda as it comes with the most essential for working with data, statistical computing and visualizations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Useful Jupyter tips</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/isds2024/post/jupyter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/isds2024/post/jupyter/</guid>
      <description>This post provides a short intro on picking up useful Jupyter hacks. We begin with a short overview of the most essential Jupyter shortcuts and skills. If you have not read the introduction to Jupyter you should do that immediately, see here.&#xA;Keyboard short cuts Editing and executing cells&#xA;enter edit mode: click inside the cell or press ENTR exit edit mode: click outside cell or press ESC. executing code within a cell is SHFT+ENTR or CTRL+ENTR (not the same!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exam project</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/isds2024/post/exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/isds2024/post/exam/</guid>
      <description>When the teaching in our course finishes, you are to hand in a project. The formal requirements are found here along with details on grading. The exam period runs until August 23, 2023, at 10 AM.&#xA;In this blog post we want to expand a little bit on how a good project will look. The goal of the project is to pose an interesting question and attempt to answer it by collecting publicly available data.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
